# SHADIDY KATIMA

# Tanzania, Dar es Salaam P.O.Box 32312 | +255 716 252197 | katima\_shadidy@yahoo.co.uk

#### **Professional Summary**

Agile Database administrator, programmer and web developer with deep and wide-ranging IT and Computer Science experience. Strive to build database, website, software and network that is as structurally, semantically and aesthetically cohesive as it is intuitive for the user. Work collaboratively to isolate problem domains and implement simple and repeatable solutions.

#### Skills

- MySQL
- Graphic Design
- Programming
- Content Management Systems
- Database Administrator
- Database design
- Web development and Maintenance

#### **Education**

Masters of Computer Science and Technology  Nanjing University of Information Science and Technology, P. R. China.	September 2014 – July 2016
Bachelor of Information Technology Institute of Accountancy Arusha, Tanzania	September 2010 – July 2013
Advance Certificate for Secondary Education Examination (ACSEE)  St Mary's Secondary School	February 2008 – February 2010
Certificate for Secondary School Education Examination (CSEE)  St Mary's Secondary School	September 2003 – September 2007

#### **Working Experience**

Feb 2018 - To date

Kampala International University in Tanzania: Systems Analyst

- To define application problems by conferring with clients, evaluating procedure and processes
- Develop solutions by preparing and evaluating alternative workflow solution
- Ensure operation by training clients personnel; providing support
- Provide reference by writing documentation
- Validate result by testing programs
- Accomplish information systems and organization mission by completing related results as needed

### Kampala International University in Tanzania: Assistant Lecturer

- To mentor younger academics
- Preparation of course files, outline, contents and on time submission
- To teach and supervise undergraduate students
- To develop marking schemes for the course taught
- To set, invigilate, mark and submit result on time

July 2013 – Feb 2018

### JSB EnviDep Ltd: IT consultancy part-time

- Service and maintain the company computers
- Develop and maintain the company website (www.jsbenvidep.com)
- Develop the company webmail
- Prepare budget for needed ICT equipment

#### **Mother Tongue(s)**

#### Swahili

# Foreign Language(s)

	Reading	Listening	Speaking
English	Proficient User	Proficient User	Proficient User
Chinese	Basic User	Basic User	Basic User

# **Publication**

Secured web database based on ABE, 2016

# **Honors and Awards**

**CSC** (China Scholarship Council) Master Scholarship for MSc in Computer Science and Technology, Nanjing University of Information Science and Technology, China, **2014-2016** 

### **Database Certifications**

UNIQUE Academy Ltd

October 2013–February 2014

- Oracle SQL expert
- Oracle Certified Associate (OCA)
- Oracle Certified Professional (OCP)

# Besant Technology (India)

October 2019-November 2019

• Ms SQL Developer Training

# NI Analytics India

October 2019-November 2019

• Data Analytics with Python

### Referee

Prof. Chun Yongyin Nanjing University of Information Science and Technology 219 Ningliu Road, Pukou District, Nanjing, Jiangsu, 21004, P.R China

Tel: +86 182 5208 8019

Email: <a href="mailto:chunyong.yin@qq.com">chunyong.yin@qq.com</a>

Khadija Porry Deputy Director, Human Resource Management, Kampala International University in Tanzania (KIUT), P. O. Box 32312

Tel: +255 745 984 908

Email: khadijaporry@gmail.com